Get better clarity with your spoken English by fully understanding all the consonant sounds we have in American English.
通过充分理解美式英语中的所有辅音音来提高你的英语口语清晰度。
Today is a compilation of every single consonant sound you need to know.
今天是你需要知道的每一个辅音音的汇编。
Some will be easy for you.
有些对你来说会很简单。
You have them in your own native language.
你在自己的母语中也有这些音。
Great! Just practice the words.
太好了！只需练习这些单词。
Others will be tricky, unfamiliar.
其他的会比较棘手，不太熟悉。
Use the photos to study the position and the up close slow motion shots.
使用照片来研究位置和特写慢动作镜头。
This will help make clear, for example, how much of the tongue tip needs to come through the teeth for the TH.
这将有助于清楚地了解，例如，TH音时舌尖需要伸出牙齿多少。
It's not much.
不需要太多。
Why not start with the TH?
为什么不从TH音开始呢？
Let's dive in.
让我们开始吧。
These sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这些音被配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口腔位置。
Th is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth.
Th是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔。
And th is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
而th是有声的，意味着你用声带发出声音。
The very tip of the tongue comes through the teeth.
舌尖的最前端伸出牙齿。
The air passes around the tongue.
空气绕过舌头。
The tongue is relaxed.
舌头是放松的。
There shouldn't be any pressure in the mouth or a stop quality to this sound.
口腔中不应该有任何压力或停顿的感觉。
Just nice and easy.
只需轻松自然。
Th.
Th。
The tongue has to easily vibrate between the teeth.
舌头必须在牙齿之间轻松振动。
So keep the tongue soft and relaxed.
所以保持舌头柔软和放松。
Th.
Th。
The lips don't affect this sound, so they can be transitioning to the next sound.
嘴唇不影响这个音，所以它们可以过渡到下一个音。
For example, in the THR cluster, the lips will round a little bit for the R as you make the TH.
例如，在THR组合中，发TH音时嘴唇会稍微圆起来以发R音。
Three.
Three。
Be careful with the tongue tip.
小心舌尖。
Make sure it doesn't come too far forward.
确保它不要伸得太远。
It's just the very tip that should come between the teeth.
只有舌尖的最前端应该在牙齿之间。
To make the unvoiced TH, the tongue tip absolutely has to come through the teeth.
要发无声的TH音，舌尖绝对必须伸出牙齿。
Th.
Th。
But the voiced TH can be different.
但有声的TH音可以不同。
When it's in an unstressed, quick word like these, or the.
当它在一个不重读的快速单词中时，比如these或the。
The tongue tip doesn't have to come through the teeth.
舌尖不必伸出牙齿。
It can press behind the teeth.
它可以压在牙齿后面。
Make sure the tongue isn't at the roof of the mouth, or pointing down, but pressing right in the middle, where the teeth come together.
确保舌头不是在口腔顶部，也不是向下，而是压在中间，牙齿合拢的地方。
If it's not in the right position, the sound will be wrong.
如果位置不对，发音就会错误。
Dd.
Dd。
These.
These。
Dd.
Dd。
This tongue shortcut works in these words because they're unstressed.
这个舌头捷径在这些单词中有效，因为它们是不重读的。
So when you don't bring your tongue tip through the teeth, it allows you to make these less important words quickly.
所以当你不把舌尖伸出牙齿时，它让你可以快速发出这些不太重要的单词。
These.
These。
Dd.
Dd。
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作看看这些音。
Notice how it's just the very tip that comes out of the teeth.
注意只有舌尖的最前端伸出牙齿。
The tongue is relaxed, the teeth surround it, but they're not clamping down on it.
舌头是放松的，牙齿围绕着它，但没有夹住它。
The lips and face are relaxed.
嘴唇和面部是放松的。
Throw.
Throw。
Notice how the lips are starting to flare for the R as the tongue comes through the teeth for the unvoiced TH.
注意当舌头伸出牙齿发无声的TH音时，嘴唇开始为R音张开。
Birthday.
Birthday。
Keep in mind, when you only stick the very tip of your tongue out, the movement into other sounds isn't as hard as you might think.
记住，当你只伸出舌尖时，过渡到其他音的动作并不像你想象的那么难。
Watch the tongue tip come in and flip up for the D.
看舌尖进来并翻上去发D音。
To make it more natural.
让它更自然。
Brother.
Brother。
Tongue tip through the teeth for the voiced TH.
舌尖伸出牙齿发有声的TH音。
Lips and tongue are relaxed.
嘴唇和舌头是放松的。
Worth.
Worth。
Ending in the unvoiced TH.
以无声的TH音结尾。
Again, the lips and tongue look very relaxed.
再次，嘴唇和舌头看起来非常放松。
Remember to keep your tongue relaxed and soft when you practice this sound.
记住在练习这个音时保持舌头放松和柔软。
And unvoiced TH.
和无声的TH音。
Throw.
Throw。
Birthday.
Birthday。
Brother.
Brother。
Worth.
Worth。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Other.
Other。
Th.
Th。
Other.
Other。
Either.
Either。
Th.
Th。
Either.
Either。
Though.
Though。
Thursday.
Thursday。
Th.
Th。
Thursday.
Thursday。
Nothing.
Nothing。
Th.
Th。
Nothing.
Nothing。
South.
South。
Th.
Th。
South.
South。
The R in American English is also such a tough sound for my students to get.
美式英语中的R音对我的学生来说也是一个很难掌握的音。
Here's the thing.
事情是这样的。
Most people need to simplify, do less with the tongue.
大多数人需要简化，减少舌头的动作。
Maybe round the lips a little bit more, but take out tension.
也许稍微多一点嘴唇的圆度，但要去掉紧张感。
Take a look.
看看吧。
This is truly one of the hardest sounds in American English.
这确实是美式英语中最难的音之一。
Before I go into how to make it, I want to talk about how not to make it.
在我讲如何发这个音之前，我想谈谈如何不发这个音。
In many languages, the R is made by bouncing the front part of the tongue against the roof of the mouth.
在许多语言中，R音是通过舌头的前部在口腔顶部弹跳来发出的。
Ruh.
Ruh。
In American English, this sound is the T or D between vowels, but it's quite different from the American R.
在美式英语中，这个音是元音之间的T或D音，但它与美式R音有很大不同。
Rrrrr.
Rrrrr。
You can't hold out Ruh.
你不能长时间发Ruh。
Ruh.
Ruh。
But you should be able to hold out the American R.
但你应该能够长时间发美式R音。
Rrrrr.
Rrrrr。
This consonant is voiced.
这个辅音是有声的。
There are two ways to make this sound.
有两种方法可以发这个音。
In the first way, the front part of the tongue pulls back and up, like this.
第一种方法是舌头的前部向后和向上拉，如此。
The back part of the tongue is made to hold itself, so it's fatter and thicker.
舌头的后部保持不动，使其更厚更胖。
And that's what we want here.
这就是我们想要的。
We're making the tongue fatter and thicker, so it's not as long.
我们让舌头更厚更胖，所以它不那么长。
The back doesn't move.
后部不动。
This is happening with the front and middle of the tongue.
这是舌头的前部和中部在动作。
The middle part of the tongue lifts up towards the roof of the mouth.
舌头的中部向口腔顶部抬起。
You can touch the sides of the tongue, to the sides of the roof of the mouth here, or to the inside or bottom of the side teeth, here.
你可以让舌头的两侧接触口腔顶部的两侧，或者接触侧牙的内侧或底部。
The front part of the tongue is hanging in the middle of the mouth, not touching anything.
舌头的前部悬在口腔中间，不接触任何东西。
This sound is forward and focused because of the position of the lips.
这个音是向前和集中的，因为嘴唇的位置。
The corners come in, pushing the lips away from the face.
嘴角收紧，把嘴唇推离面部。
This lip position will be a little more relaxed when the R comes at the end of a syllable.
当R音在音节末尾时，这个嘴唇位置会稍微放松一些。
We'll compare this way on the left with the other way, to make an R, on the right.
我们将左边的这种方法与右边的另一种发R音的方法进行比较。
The R can also be made by flipping the tongue tip up.
R音也可以通过翻起舌尖来发出。
The lips flare the same way.
嘴唇以同样的方式张开。
Some native speakers make the R one way, and some the other.
一些母语者用一种方法发R音，另一些用另一种。
Native speakers get the correct sound no matter the mouth position.
母语者无论口腔位置如何都能发出正确的音。
But I've found that non-native speakers often drop the jaw too much in this second method, and it makes the sound hollow.
但我发现非母语者在使用第二种方法时常常下巴掉得太多，使得音听起来空洞。
Rrr.
Rrr。
The jaw doesn't need to drop very much for this sound.
这个音不需要下巴掉得太多。
Rrr.
Rrr。
So keep this in mind as you work on one of these two methods.
所以在练习这两种方法之一时要记住这一点。
Here's the R sound on its own, not part of a word.
这是R音本身，不是单词的一部分。
You can see the lips flare.
你可以看到嘴唇张开。
Think of creating little space between the inside of your lips and your teeth.
想象在嘴唇内侧和牙齿之间创造一点空间。
Notice how little jaw drop there is.
注意下巴掉得很少。
We don't need to drop the jaw to pull the tongue back and up.
我们不需要下巴掉下来就能把舌头向后和向上拉。
The word rest.
单词rest。
When the R is at the beginning of a word, we tend to make the lips a tight circle.
当R音在单词开头时，我们倾向于让嘴唇形成一个紧的圆圈。
Again, little jaw drop as the middle of the tongue lifts to the roof of the mouth.
再次，当舌头的中部抬起到口腔顶部时，下巴掉得很少。
The word proud.
单词proud。
When R is in a beginning consonant cluster, the lips may not be as tight as in a beginning R.
当R音在开头辅音组合中时，嘴唇可能不像开头R音那样紧。
The word mother.
单词mother。
At the end of a syllable, the lip position for the R is definitely more relaxed than a beginning R, but the lips still flare.
在音节末尾，R音的嘴唇位置肯定比开头R音更放松，但嘴唇仍然张开。
Here, we compare the lip position of the beginning R in REST, above, to the ending R in MOTHER, below.
在这里，我们比较了上面的开头R音在REST中的嘴唇位置和下面的结尾R音在MOTHER中的嘴唇位置。
The ending R lip position is much more relaxed.
结尾R音的嘴唇位置要放松得多。
Thinking about the lip position will help you make a better R sound.
考虑嘴唇位置将帮助你发出更好的R音。
As you work on this consonant, practice very slowly, thinking about all three things at once.
在练习这个辅音时，慢慢地练习，同时考虑这三件事。
Very little jaw drop.
下巴掉得很少。
The tongue position, and the lip position.
舌头位置和嘴唇位置。
Remember, you can hold out this sound, so that's how you want to practice it.
记住，你可以长时间发出这个音，所以你要这样练习。
Rrrrr.
Rrrrr。
Hold it out for five or ten seconds.
长时间发出五到十秒。
Hold it out as long as you can.
尽可能长时间发出。
When you practice it in a word, do the same.
当你在单词中练习时，也要这样做。
Rrrrrrest.
Rrrrrrest。
Proud.
Proud。
Motherrrrrr.
Motherrrrrr。
The R sound.
R音。
Rest.
Rest。
Proud.
Proud。
Mother.
Mother。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Read.
Read。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Read.
Read。
Great.
Great。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Great.
Great。
Try.
Try。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Try.
Try。
Later.
Later。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Later.
Later。
Write.
Write。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Write.
Write。
Other.
Other。
Rrr.
Rrr。
Other.
Other。
And now, back to back, you'll see all the other consonant sounds in American English.
现在，你将看到美式英语中的所有其他辅音音。
We're going to start with the pairs, like TH, where there are two sounds together, because one is voiced and the other is unvoiced, but they have the same mouth position.
我们将从成对的音开始，比如TH，其中有两个音在一起，因为一个是有声的，另一个是无声的，但它们有相同的口腔位置。
Then we'll get into single sounds, like R.
然后我们将进入单个音，比如R。
The P and B consonants.
P和B辅音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个音被配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口腔位置。
P is unvoiced, p, meaning only air passes through the mouth.
P是无声的，p，意味着只有空气通过口腔。
And B is voiced, b, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
而B是有声的，b，意味着你用声带发出声音。
B.
B。
The lips stay together while the teeth part a little.
嘴唇保持在一起，而牙齿稍微分开。
The tongue position doesn't matter for these consonants, so the tongue can start to get into position for the next sound.
舌头的位置对这些辅音没有影响，所以舌头可以开始为下一个音做好准备。
For example, if the next sound is the R consonant, the tongue can move back and up for the R, while the lips close for the B.
例如，如果下一个音是R辅音，舌头可以为R音向后和向上移动，而嘴唇为B音闭合。
Bring.
Bring。
Let's see the sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作看看这些音。
Then release.
然后释放。
These are stop consonants.
这些是爆破音。
In stop consonants, there are two parts.
在爆破音中，有两个部分。
There's a stop of the air flow, and a release.
有一个气流的停止和一个释放。
The stop of the air flow happens as the lips close.
气流的停止发生在嘴唇闭合时。
Happen.
Happen。
The release is when the lips part and the air comes through.
释放是当嘴唇分开，空气通过时。
Pn.
Happen.
发生。
Sometimes, native speakers don't release stop consonants when they come at the end of a sentence, or when the next word begins with a consonant.
有时，母语者在句子结尾或下一个单词以辅音开头时，不会释放爆破音。
For example, the common phrase, what's up?
例如，常见短语“what's up?”
My lips closed in the P position, but I didn't release the air.
我的嘴唇闭合在P的位置，但我没有释放气流。
What's up?
Another example, nap time.
另一个例子，午睡时间。
Nap time.
午睡时间。
My lips came together for the P, but they didn't release the air.
我的嘴唇合在一起形成P，但没有释放气流。
I stopped the air with my lips, then released it with the next sound, the T consonant.
我用嘴唇阻止了气流，然后在下一个声音T辅音时释放。
Nap time.
午睡时间。
Let's look at some words up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察一些单词。
The word best.
单词“best”。
The lips press together, and then release into the EH as in bed vowel.
嘴唇压在一起，然后释放成“EH”音，如“bed”中的元音。
The word spot.
单词“spot”。
The lips press together, and then release into the AH as in father vowel.
嘴唇压在一起，然后释放成“AH”音，如“father”中的元音。
The word rip.
单词“rip”。
The lips press together, and then release.
嘴唇压在一起，然后释放。
The P and B consonants.
P和B辅音。
Best.
Spot.
Rip.
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Bring.
Bb.
Baby.
Job.
Bb.
Peace.
Pp.
Price.
Up.
Pp.
CH and J consonants.
CH和J辅音。
The CH and J consonants are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
CH和J辅音配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口型。
CH is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth, and J is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
CH是无声的，意味着只有气流通过口腔，而J是有声的，意味着你用声带发声。
J.
These consonants have a stop consonant component, but unlike stop consonants, they're always released.
这些辅音有一个爆破音成分，但与爆破音不同，它们总是被释放。
They each contain two sounds.
它们各包含两个声音。
For the CH, we're combining the T, T, and the SH, sh, to make ch.
对于CH，我们结合T和SH，形成ch。
For the J sound, we're combining dd and zh to make jj.
对于J音，我们结合dd和zh，形成jj。
The teeth come together and the lips flare, just like in the sh and zh sounds.
牙齿合在一起，嘴唇张开，就像在sh和zh音中一样。
But the tongue position is like the T and dd.
但舌头的位置像T和dd。
Sounds.
声音。
The tongue lifts so the front, flat part of the tongue touches the roof of the mouth.
舌头抬起，使舌头的前平面部分接触口腔的顶部。
We stop the air in our throat, and then we release everything.
我们在喉咙中阻止气流，然后释放一切。
Ch.
Jj.
We release the air at the vocal cords, release the tongue down from the roof of the mouth, release the teeth so they part a little, and release the lips by relaxing them.
我们在声带处释放气流，从口腔顶部释放舌头，牙齿稍微分开，放松嘴唇释放。
Ch.
Jj.
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这些声音。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合在一起。
Then the release.
然后释放。
The word JAR.
单词“JAR”。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合在一起。
Then release into the AH as in FATHER vowel.
然后释放成“AH”音，如“FATHER”中的元音。
The word BATCH.
单词“BATCH”。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合在一起。
Then release.
然后释放。
The CH and J consonants.
CH和J辅音。
JAR.
CHART.
BATCH.
Full words.
完整单词。
Practice with me.
跟我练习。
Chase.
Ch.
Attach.
Teacher.
Ch.
Danger.
J.
Just.
General.
J.
The T and D consonant sounds.
T和D辅音音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个声音配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口型。
Tt is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth, and dd is voiced, meaning dd.
Tt是无声的，意味着只有气流通过口腔，而dd是有声的，意味着dd。
You make a sound with the vocal cords.
你用声带发声。
These consonants are complicated because the way Americans pronounce them isn't always what you'll find in a dictionary.
这些辅音很复杂，因为美国人发音的方式并不总是字典中所描述的。
First, let's talk about the true pronunciation.
首先，让我们谈谈真正的发音。
These are stop consonants, which means there are two parts.
这些是爆破音，这意味着有两个部分。
First, a stop in the airflow, and second, a release.
首先是气流的阻止，其次是释放。
We stop here by closing the vocal cords, and lift the tongue so the flat, top part is at the roof of the mouth.
我们通过闭合声带来阻止气流，并抬起舌头，使平坦的顶部部分在口腔顶部。
It's far forward, almost touching the back of the top front teeth.
它靠前，几乎接触到上前牙的后面。
The teeth come together, and we release all three parts at once.
牙齿合在一起，我们同时释放所有三个部分。
The tongue comes down from the roof of the mouth, the teeth part, and we release the air in the throat.
舌头从口腔顶部下来，牙齿分开，我们在喉咙中释放气流。
Tt.
Dd.
Just like with other stop consonants, we want to release them into the next sound.
就像其他爆破音一样，我们希望将它们释放到下一个声音中。
Let's look at the true T and D consonants up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察真正的T和D辅音。
Tt.
The air comes together, and the top, front of the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
气流合在一起，舌头的前部在口腔顶部。
The air stops in the throat.
气流在喉咙中停止。
Then, the teeth part, and the tongue pulls down to release.
然后，牙齿分开，舌头下拉释放。
The word DESK.
单词“DESK”。
The teeth close, and the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
牙齿闭合，舌头在口腔顶部。
Then, everything releases right into the EH as in BED vowel.
然后，一切释放成“EH”音，如“BED”中的元音。
The word STICK.
单词“STICK”。
The teeth close, and the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
牙齿闭合，舌头在口腔顶部。
Then, everything releases right into the IH as in SIT vowel.
然后，一切释放成“IH”音，如“SIT”中的元音。
The word EXPECT.
单词“EXPECT”。
The teeth nearly close, and the tongue is at the roof of the mouth.
牙齿几乎闭合，舌头在口腔顶部。
Then, the teeth release just a bit.
然后，牙齿稍微释放。
There's no next sound to release into, so the movement is minimal for the release.
没有下一个声音可以释放，所以释放的动作很小。
The tongue releases down.
舌头向下释放。
It's possible to make the true D without the teeth coming together.
可以在不让牙齿合在一起的情况下发出真正的D音。
Said.
Dd.
Because of the voice in this sound, we can still release it.
由于这个声音中有声带的参与，我们仍然可以释放它。
Said.
Dd.
But to make the true T, the teeth do have to come together or nearly together.
但要发出真正的T音，牙齿必须合在一起或几乎合在一起。
Said.
Set.
Tt.
That was the true T and true D.
那是真正的T和真正的D。
If the T or D are at the end of a sentence, or if the next word begins with a consonant, then we make a stop T or stop D.
如果T或D在句子末尾，或者下一个单词以辅音开头，那么我们会发出停顿T或停顿D。
We stop the air, but we don't release it.
我们阻止气流，但不释放。
You lift your tongue into position, stop the air, and that's it.
你抬起舌头到位，阻止气流，仅此而已。
For example, the word MAD.
例如，单词“MAD”。
MAD.
Notice the last sound is...
注意最后的声音是...
The beginning of the D.
D的开始。
With the vocal cords engaged, because it's a voiced consonant.
因为它是有声辅音，所以声带参与。
And that's all.
仅此而已。
I don't release.
我不释放。
A release would sound like this.
释放会听起来像这样。
MAD.
Dd.
But instead, I say MAD.
但我说的是MAD。
Dd.
Leaving my tongue tip up.
舌尖保持上扬。
Now let's look at an example with a T followed by another consonant.
现在让我们看一个T后面跟着另一个辅音的例子。
The phrase, not for me.
短语“not for me”。
Here the T is followed by F.
这里T后面是F。
I stop the air.
我阻止气流。
Not.
And then, without releasing, go into the F sound.
然后，在不释放的情况下进入F音。
Not for.
Not for me.
With stop consonants, we do stop the air in the throat.
对于爆破音，我们在喉咙中阻止气流。
So I don't have to move my tongue up into position for the T to stop the sound.
所以我不必将舌头抬到T的位置来阻止声音。
In this phrase, not for me, I touch the roof of my mouth with a part of the tongue that's further back.
在这个短语“not for me”中，我用舌头更靠后的部分接触口腔顶部。
Not.
My tongue tip can stay down.
我的舌尖可以保持下垂。
I go into the next sound.
我进入下一个声音。
Not for.
I'll bring my tongue up for the stop T if the next sound also requires the tongue being at the roof of the mouth.
如果下一个声音也需要舌头在口腔顶部，我会抬起舌头来发出停顿T。
When I say, not for me, instead of, not for me, the words are more connected and the sentence is smoother.
当我说“not for me”而不是“not for me”时，单词更连贯，句子更流畅。
That's what we want in American English.
这就是我们在美式英语中想要的。
And that's why we use the stop T instead of the true T in these cases.
这就是为什么在这些情况下我们使用停顿T而不是真正的T。
Not for me.
Let's look at a stop, up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察一个停顿。
Here's the word, what.
这是单词“what”。
I don't release the T at the end.
我不释放结尾的T。
The tongue goes to the roof of the mouth.
舌头到达口腔顶部。
But then I just stop the air.
但我只是阻止气流。
My teeth aren't together and I don't release.
我的牙齿没有合在一起，我不释放。
The lips simply close.
嘴唇只是闭合。
What.
Here's what it looks like with a true T.
这是带有真正T的样子。
The teeth come together, then a subtle release.
牙齿合在一起，然后微妙地释放。
Compare the ending.
比较结尾。
The top is what with a stop T and the bottom is what with a true T.
上面是带有停顿T的“what”，下面是带有真正T的“what”。
For the stop T, the teeth don't come together because they don't need to release.
对于停顿T，牙齿不合在一起，因为它们不需要释放。
The air simply stops with the tongue in position.
气流只是用舌头在位置上停止。
For the true T, we bring the teeth together so the tongue, teeth, and air release.
对于真正的T，我们让牙齿合在一起，以便舌头、牙齿和气流释放。
The stop T and D relate to the true T and D.
停顿T和D与真正的T和D有关。
We simply skip the release.
我们只是跳过释放。
But when the T or D come between two vowels or diphthongs, or after an R and before a vowel or diphthong, we make a different sound.
但当T或D位于两个元音或双元音之间，或在R之后和元音或双元音之前时，我们发出不同的声音。
One exception.
一个例外。
If the T or D starts a stressed syllable, then it's a true T or D.
如果T或D开始一个重读音节，那么它是一个真正的T或D。
But in other cases, when the T or D consonants come between two vowels or diphthongs, or after an R and before a vowel or diphthong, we make a flap sound.
但在其他情况下，当T或D辅音位于两个元音或双元音之间，或在R之后和元音或双元音之前时，我们发出一个轻拍音。
This is different from the true and stop T and D because we don't stop the sound.
这与真正的和停顿的T和D不同，因为我们不停止声音。
We don't hold anything.
我们不保持任何东西。
We simply let the front part of the tongue bounce against the roof of the mouth without stopping the flow of air.
我们只是让舌头的前部在口腔顶部轻轻弹跳，而不停止气流。
The flap T and flap D sound the same.
闪音T和闪音D听起来是一样的。
The T in matter is the same as the D in matter.
在“matter”这个词中，T和D是一样的。
Matter.
This sounds just like the R in many languages.
这个听起来就像许多语言中的R音。
But in American English, it's the flap T or flap D.
但在美式英语中，这是闪音T或闪音D。
In my videos, I use the D symbol for this sound.
在我的视频中，我用D符号来表示这个音。
This sound, however, isn't a stop consonant anymore.
然而，这个音不再是一个爆破音。
Let's look at some words with a flap up close and in slow motion.
让我们仔细慢动作看看一些带有闪音的单词。
The word city.
单词“city”。
Here, the T comes between two vowel sounds, so it's a flap.
这里，T在两个元音之间，所以是一个闪音。
The tongue is in position for the IH vowel.
舌头处于IH元音的位置。
Watch how it flaps the roof of the mouth quickly.
看它如何快速拍打上颚。
The air doesn't stop.
气流没有停止。
That flap was fast, even in slow motion.
即使在慢动作中，那个闪音也很快。
Let's watch again.
让我们再看一遍。
The whole word one more time.
整个单词再来一遍。
The word party.
单词“party”。
Here, the T comes after an R and before a vowel, so it's a flap.
这里，T在R之后和元音之前，所以是一个闪音。
The tongue is back and up for the R.
舌头向后并向上以发R音。
Watch it flap.
看它如何拍打。
And come down from the flap.
然后从闪音中下来。
The air didn't stop.
气流没有停止。
Watch the whole word one more time.
再看整个单词一遍。
The word tidy.
单词“tidy”。
Here, the D comes after a diphthong and before a vowel, so it's a flap D.
这里，D在双元音之后和元音之前，所以是一个闪音D。
Watch the tongue flap.
看舌头如何拍打。
The whole word one more time.
整个单词再来一遍。
And after.
然后。
Party.
Then you can really feel the tongue flap, bouncing against the roof of the mouth.
然后你可以真正感觉到舌头拍打，撞击上颚。
Remember, this isn't represented in dictionaries.
记住，这在字典中没有表示。
They will show the symbol for the true T, party, even though Americans pronounce it party.
他们会显示真正的T的符号，party，即使美国人发音是party。
So remember the rule.
所以记住这个规则。
When a T or D comes between vowels and diphthongs, they're after an R before a vowel or diphthong, like party, unless it starts a stressed syllable, flap the tongue.
当T或D在元音和双元音之间时，它们在R之后和元音或双元音之前，比如party，除非它开始一个重读音节，拍打舌头。
Sometimes we drop the T or D completely.
有时我们会完全省略T或D。
We leave the sounds out.
我们会把这些音省略掉。
This is an American habit.
这是一个美国人的习惯。
If you look up the words in the dictionary, the sounds are there.
如果你在字典中查找这些单词，这些音是存在的。
There are two cases when you might hear an American drop a T or D.
有两种情况你可能会听到美国人省略T或D。
First, when the T or D comes between two consonant sounds.
首先，当T或D在两个辅音之间。
For example, exactly.
例如，“exactly”。
This word has the K, T, L consonants together.
这个词有K、T、L三个辅音在一起。
But most people pronounce it without the T.
但大多数人发音时不发T。
Exactly.
Full pronunciation, exactly.
完整发音，exactly。
Common pronunciation, exactly.
常见发音，exactly。
Dropping the T between two consonants, simplifies the pronunciation.
在两个辅音之间省略T，简化了发音。
Also, we often drop the T when it comes after an N.
此外，我们经常在T在N之后时省略T。
Many Americans say center instead of center, or interview instead of interview.
许多美国人说“center”而不是“center”，或者“interview”而不是“interview”。
This is a big topic.
这是一个大话题。
I have a whole series of videos on the pronunciation of T and D, which you can find on my website.
我有一整套关于T和D发音的视频系列，你可以在我的网站上找到。
The true T and D sounds.
真正的T和D音。
Desk, stick, expect.
Stop T and D.
停顿T和D。
Mad, not, what.
The flap T and D.
闪音T和D。
City, party, tidy.
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Best, tt, best.
Time, tt, time.
Do, dd, do.
Odd, dd, odd.
There's no way to make a Stop T sound on its own because it isn't a sound.
没有办法单独发出停顿T音，因为它不是一个音。
It's a lack of sound.
它是一个无声的停顿。
Cut, cut.
Better, rr, better.
The F and V consonants.
F和V辅音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个音被配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口腔位置。
Fff is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth, and vv is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
Fff是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔，而vv是有声的，意味着你用声带发出声音。
Vv.
To make these sounds, the bottom lip lifts and touches the very bottom of the top front teeth.
要发出这些音，下唇抬起并接触上前牙的底部。
Fff, vv.
The top lip lifts a little bit to give it out of the way of the bottom lip.
上唇稍微抬起，以便让出下唇的空间。
You don't want to see your bottom lip disappear.
你不希望看到你的下唇消失。
Fff.
It's actually the inside of the lip, here, that makes contact with the teeth.
实际上是这里的唇内侧与牙齿接触。
Fff, vv.
The tongue should stay relaxed so the air can easily push through, causing the bottom lip to vibrate against the top teeth.
舌头应保持放松，以便空气可以轻松通过，使下唇在上牙上振动。
Let's look at the sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们仔细慢动作看看这些音。
The top lip lifts so the bottom lip has room to vibrate against the bottom of the top front teeth.
上唇抬起，以便下唇有空间在上前牙的底部振动。
Very.
Bottom lip goes to the bottom of the top front teeth.
下唇到上前牙的底部。
Flavor.
The bottom lip goes to the top front teeth for the F, and again for the V.
下唇到上前牙发F音，再次发V音。
Enough.
Bottom lip to top front teeth.
下唇到上前牙。
When you work on these consonants, and words with these consonants, watch yourself and make sure your bottom lip doesn't curl in.
当你练习这些辅音和带有这些辅音的单词时，观察自己，确保你的下唇没有卷进去。
Fff, vv.
Remember, it's the inside of the lip that makes these sounds.
记住，是唇的内侧发出这些音。
The F and V consonants.
F和V辅音。
Very.
Flavor.
Enough.
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Live.
Vv.
Value.
Provide.
Vv.
Fresh.
Fff.
Offer.
Tough.
Fff.
The G and K consonant sounds.
G和K辅音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个音被配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口腔位置。
Kk is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth.
Kk是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔。
And gk is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
而gk是有声的，意味着你用声带发出声音。
Gk.
The K consonants are stop consonants, which means there are two parts to each sound.
K辅音是爆破音，这意味着每个音有两个部分。
First, a stop in the air flow, and second, a release.
首先，气流的停止，然后是释放。
We stop the flow of air here, closing our vocal cords, while the back part of the tongue reaches up to touch the soft palate.
我们在这里停止气流，闭合声带，同时舌头的后部抬起接触软腭。
I'm going to slow down the K sound in the word, back.
我将慢动作演示单词“back”中的K音。
See if you can hear the stop of air before the release.
看看你能否听到释放前的气流停止。
Back.
Kk.
Here you can see the tongue position.
这里你可以看到舌头的位置。
The back of the tongue reaches up to touch the soft palate, which is closed.
舌头的后部抬起接触软腭，软腭是闭合的。
The tip of the tongue can remain forward, lightly touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌尖可以保持向前，轻轻接触下前牙的后面。
The jaw drops a little bit, and the lips are open.
下巴稍微下垂，嘴唇是张开的。
Kk.
Gk.
The lip position doesn't matter for these sounds, so the lips might start forming the next sound, like in the word, great.
嘴唇的位置对这些音没有影响，所以嘴唇可能开始形成下一个音，比如在单词“great”中。
Here, the lips can start taking the position for the R as we make the G.
在这里，嘴唇可以在发G音时开始形成R音的位置。
Gk.
Great.
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们仔细慢动作看看这些音。
Touch the soft palate.
接触软腭。
Then the tongue releases.
然后舌头释放。
Sometimes, to make a sentence smoother, the words more linked together, native speakers will skip the release of a stop consonant when the next word begins with a consonant.
有时，为了使句子更流畅，单词更连贯，母语者会在下一个单词以辅音开头时跳过爆破音的释放。
For example, the phrase, back to work.
例如，短语“back to work”。
Back to.
I'm not saying, back to.
我没有说“back to”。
Kk.
With the full release of the K.
完整释放K音。
I'm holding the air for a fraction of a second with my throat, making that stop, then I go right into the release of the T consonant.
我用喉咙停顿一瞬间，做出那个停顿，然后直接进入T辅音的释放。
Back to.
Back to work.
Without the release of the K in back, the two words flow together more easily, making it smoother.
在“back”中省略K的释放，使两个单词更容易连在一起，更流畅。
Notice I do make a light release of the K in the word, work.
注意我在单词“work”中轻轻释放了K音。
Can you hear it?
你能听到吗？
Back to work.
Let's look at some words up close and in slow motion.
让我们仔细慢动作看看一些单词。
The word, keep.
单词“keep”。
Because the tongue lifts at the back and does not require much jaw drop, it's hard to see this sound in this word.
因为舌头在后部抬起，不需要太多下巴下垂，所以在这个单词中很难看到这个音。
The lips need to round for the next sound, R.
嘴唇需要为下一个音R圆起来。
The lip position doesn't change the G sound.
嘴唇的位置不会改变G音。
It's a little easier to see the back of the tongue move when it's at the end of a word like this word, egg.
在单词结尾时更容易看到舌头后部的移动，比如单词“egg”。
The tongue lifts in the back, then releases.
舌头在后部抬起，然后释放。
The G and K consonants.
G和K辅音。
Keep.
Green.
Egg.
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Go.
G.
Again.
Big.
G.
Cry.
Cry.rà The S and Z consonant sounds.
Cry.rà S和Z辅音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take take the same mouth position.
这两个音被配对在一起，因为它们使用相同的口腔位置。
SS is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth.
SS是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔。
And ZZZ is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
而ZZZ是有声的，意味着你用声带发出声音。
ZZZ.
To make the sounds, the lips part, and the corners pull back a little while the teeth themselves lightly touch.
要发出这些音，嘴唇分开，嘴角稍微向后拉，同时牙齿轻轻接触。
SS, ZZZ.
There are two ways to make these sounds.
有两种方法可以发出这些音。
One, with the tip of the tongue down, lightly touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
一种是舌尖向下，轻轻接触下前牙的后面。
Or, by pointing the tip of the tongue up.
或者，舌尖向上。
You may find that the position of the tongue tip depends on the sounds around the S and Z.
你可能会发现舌尖的位置取决于S和Z周围的音。
Let's look at these sounds up close, and in slow motion.
让我们仔细慢动作看看这些音。
The teeth lightly touch, tongue tip is down, and you can see a lot of the tongue through the teeth.
牙齿轻轻接触，舌尖向下，你可以通过牙齿看到很多舌头。
Sip.
Again, teeth lightly touch, the tongue tip is pointed down.
再次，牙齿轻轻接触，舌尖向下。
Miss.
The tongue tip stays down as the teeth come together.
舌尖保持向下，牙齿合拢。
This time, you'll see the tongue tip point up before the teeth close.
这次，你会看到舌尖在牙齿闭合之前向上指。
And up.
向上。
The S and Z sounds.
S 和 Z 的发音。
Sip.
Sip。
Miss.
Miss。
Fizz.
Fizz。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
the letter S can make the Z sound.
字母 S 可以发出 Z 的声音。
Some.
Some。
Must.
Must。
Less.
Less。
Zip.
Zip。
Zzz.
Zzz。
Zip.
Zip。
Cousin.
Cousin。
Zzz.
Zzz。
Cousin.
Cousin。
Easy.
Easy。
Zzz.
Zzz。
Easy.
Easy。
The SH and ZZZ consonant sounds.
SH 和 ZZZ 辅音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个声音配对在一起，因为它们的口型相同。
SH is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth.
SH 是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔。
And ZZZ is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
而 ZZZ 是有声的，意味着你用声带发出声音。
ZZZ.
ZZZ。
To make these sounds, the teeth come together.
要发出这些声音，牙齿要合在一起。
The corners of the lips come in, and the lips flare.
嘴角收拢，嘴唇张开。
The tongue lifts, so the front, middle part of the tongue is very close to the roof of the mouth.
舌头抬起，所以舌头的前中部非常接近上颚。
But not touching it.
但不接触它。
The tongue tip points forward, but doesn't touch anything.
舌尖向前指，但不接触任何东西。
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这些声音。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合在一起。
In the word SHOP, the SH is at the beginning of the word.
在单词 SHOP 中，SH 在单词的开头。
In the word WISH, it's at the end.
在单词 WISH 中，它在结尾。
In the word ASIA, the ZZZ sound is in the middle.
在单词 ASIA 中，ZZZ 声音在中间。
The mouth position is always the same.
口型始终相同。
Teeth together, lips flare.
牙齿合在一起，嘴唇张开。
The SH and ZZZ consonants.
SH 和 ZZZ 辅音。
SHOP.
SHOP。
WISH.
WISH。
ASIA.
ASIA。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Should.
Should。
SH.
SH。
Should.
Should。
Special.
Special。
SH.
SH。
Special.
Special。
Wash.
Wash。
SH.
SH。
Wash.
Wash。
Measure.
Measure。
SH.
SH。
Measure.
Measure。
Garage.
Garage。
SH.
SH。
Garage.
Garage。
Usual.
Usual。
SH.
SH。
Usual.
Usual。
The H consonant sound.
H 辅音。
This sound is simply made, H, by passing air through a very slightly constricted passage, either between the tongue and the roof of the mouth, H, or in the throat, H.
这个声音很简单，通过一个非常轻微收缩的通道发出气流，H，要么在舌头和上颚之间，要么在喉咙里。
This is an unvoiced consonant.
这是一个无声的辅音。
Part the lips and press the tongue down in the back just a little.
分开嘴唇，轻轻压下舌头的后部。
If you don't constrict the air passage at all, there's no sound.
如果你完全不收缩气流通道，就没有声音。
If you lift the back of your tongue and constrict too much, you'll feel the vibration of the soft palate bouncing on the tongue.
如果你抬起舌头的后部并收缩得太多，你会感觉到软腭在舌头上振动。
This is too heavy.
这太重了。
The lips and jaw don't affect this sound, so your mouth can be in position for the next sound when you're making the H.
嘴唇和下巴不影响这个声音，所以当你发 H 的时候，你的嘴可以为下一个声音做好准备。
For example, the word HOW.
例如，单词 HOW。
How.
How。
The lips, jaw, and tongue take the beginning position of the OW as in NOW diphthong.
嘴唇、下巴和舌头取 OW 的起始位置，如 NOW 的双元音。
H.
H。
How.
How。
Let's look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察。
The sound by itself.
单独的声音。
The jaw is relaxed and the lips part.
下巴放松，嘴唇分开。
The word HIGH.
单词 HIGH。
There's nothing to see at the beginning of this word.
在这个单词的开头没有什么可看的。
The H sound happens without changing what the lips do for the AI as in BY diphthong.
H 声音发生时不改变嘴唇为 AI 的双元音 BY 的动作。
The word WHO.
单词 WHO。
Again, there's nothing to see at the beginning of this word.
同样，在这个单词的开头没有什么可看的。
The H sound happens without changing what the lips do for the next sound.
H 声音发生时不改变嘴唇为下一个声音的动作。
The OO as in BOO vowel.
OO 如 BOO 的元音。
This sound is most common at the beginning of a word and never occurs at the end of a word in American English, but the letter H does.
这个声音最常见于单词的开头，在美式英语中从不出现在单词的结尾，但字母 H 会。
The H sound.
H 声音。
High.
High。
Who.
Who。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Hope.
Hope。
History.
History。
Ahead.
Ahead。
Behind.
Behind。
Here.
Here。
Somehow.
Somehow。
L consonant sound.
L 辅音。
This sound is especially difficult.
这个声音特别难。
There are actually two kinds of Ls, and they're not made the same way.
实际上有两种 L，它们的发音方式不同。
But if you look up a word in the dictionary, there's only one International Phonetic Alphabet symbol for both kinds of L.
但如果你查字典，国际音标只有一个符号表示这两种 L。
In this video, you'll learn when to make which kind of L.
在这个视频中，你将学习何时发哪种 L。
This is what most people think of when they think of an L.
这就是大多数人想到 L 时的印象。
The L is a light L when it comes before the vowel or diphthong in a syllable.
当 L 在音节中出现在元音或双元音之前时，它是轻 L。
For example, let's, flake, release.
例如，let's, flake, release。
There are two different ways native speakers make this sound.
母语者发这个声音有两种不同的方式。
The tip is touching the roof of the mouth, just behind the front teeth.
舌尖触碰上颚，就在前牙的后面。
This is not the same as the T, D, and N tongue positions, where the tongue lifts so the top is touching the roof of the mouth.
这与 T, D 和 N 的舌位不同，T, D 和 N 的舌头抬起，使顶部接触上颚。
This is the tip.
这是舌尖。
Another way native speakers make this sound looks like the TH, with the tongue tip touching the bottom of the top front teeth.
母语者发这个声音的另一种方式看起来像 TH，舌尖触碰上前牙的底部。
The tongue is not as firm than the TH sound, pushing up on the top teeth.
舌头不像 TH 声音那样紧，推上上牙。
The tongue is not as loose or relaxed in the L as it is in the TH.
在 L 中，舌头不像在 TH 中那样松或放松。
Let's look at the light L up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察轻 L。
Here's one way to make the L, with the tongue tip coming through the teeth to press up on the bottom of the top front teeth.
这是发 L 的一种方式，舌尖穿过牙齿，压在上前牙的底部。
Here's the second way to make the light L.
这是发轻 L 的第二种方式。
The tip at the roof of the mouth, just behind the teeth.
舌尖在上颚，就在牙齿后面。
Here's the word lack.
这是单词 lack。
The tongue comes through the teeth to make the light L.
舌头穿过牙齿发轻 L。
The word slow.
单词 slow。
The light L is made with the tongue tip at the roof of the mouth.
轻 L 是用舌尖在上颚发出的。
The second kind of L is the dark L.
第二种 L 是重 L。
This is the sound that happens when the L comes after the vowel or diphthong in a word or syllable, like real or Google.
当 L 在单词或音节中出现在元音或双元音之后时，这就是重 L，比如 real 或 Google。
This sound has two parts, but many Americans leave out the second part in most cases.
这个声音有两个部分，但许多美国人在大多数情况下省略了第二部分。
You should too.
你也应该这样做。
It makes it easier to pronounce.
这使得发音更容易。
The first and most important part of the dark L is the dark sound.
重 L 的第一个也是最重要的部分是重音。
This defines the dark L.
这定义了重 L。
To make this sound, you don't lift your tongue tip.
要发出这个声音，你不抬起舌尖。
Instead, it's down, touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
相反，它向下，触碰下前牙的后面。
The back part of the tongue pulls back towards the throat.
舌头的后部向喉咙方向拉。
You can see there isn't much jaw drop, and the lips are relaxed.
你可以看到下巴没有太多下垂，嘴唇是放松的。
You should feel the vibration in the throat and not the face.
你应该感觉到喉咙而不是脸部的振动。
The back part of the tongue presses down or shifts back.
舌头的后部向下压或向后移动。
This is an important part of the sound.
这是声音的重要部分。
Most Americans will stop there when making the dark L.
大多数美国人在发重 L 时会停在这里。
Unless they're linking into a word that begins with an L, or a sound with a similar position, like N, T, or D.
除非他们要连接到以 L 开头的单词，或位置相似的声音，如 N, T 或 D。
In that case, go ahead and make the second part of the dark L.
在这种情况下，继续发重 L 的第二部分。
The second part of the dark L is the light L.
重 L 的第二部分是轻 L。
Bring your tongue tip up to the roof of the mouth or through the teeth.
将舌尖抬到上颚或穿过牙齿。
Some native speakers make the full dark L, both parts, all the way up to the tongue.
一些母语者会完整地发出重 L，两个部分，直到舌头。
What's important is the dark sound.
重要的是重音。
Make it with the back of the tongue.
用舌头的后部发出。
And make sure you never leave that part out.
确保你永远不要省略那部分。
Llll.
Llll。
Again, the dark L has two parts.
再次，重 L 有两个部分。
The first and most important part, the tongue pulls back or presses down in the back.
第一个也是最重要的部分，舌头在后部向后拉或向下压。
The second part, which is often left out.
第二部分，通常被省略。
Either option for the light L, here, the option with the tongue tip at the roof of the mouth is pictured.
轻 L 的任一选项，这里，舌尖在上颚的选项被展示。
Let's look at the dark L up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察重 L。
The word feel.
单词 feel。
The tongue tip arches in the front for the EE vowel.
舌尖在前部为 EE 元音拱起。
Watch as the tongue lowers in the back.
观察舌头在后部下降。
Now the tongue is lowered, pulling back a little bit in the back.
现在舌头在后部下降，稍微向后拉。
It's hard to see because of the lips, but the tongue tip of the tongue is still forward.
因为嘴唇的原因很难看到，但舌尖仍然在前面。
Notice that the lips are relaxed.
注意嘴唇是放松的。
The word recall.
单词 recall。
The dark part is made with the back of the tongue as the jaw closes.
重音部分是用舌头的后部发出的，当下巴闭合时。
This time, the dark L does end with the second part, the light L.
这次，重 L 以第二部分结束，轻 L。
The tongue tip quickly comes through the teeth.
舌尖迅速穿过牙齿。
Lips are relaxed.
嘴唇是放松的。
The relaxation of the lips is important in the dark L.
嘴唇的放松在重 L 中很重要。
Non-native speakers want to round or flare the lips, which brings the sound forward and changes it.
非母语者想要圆或张开嘴唇，这会将声音向前带并改变它。
But the dark sound is made back here.
但重音是在这里发出的。
Leave the lips relaxed so the sound can be made in the back of the mouth.
让嘴唇放松，以便声音可以在口腔的后部发出。
When you look at the International Phonetic Alphabet Transcription for a word in a dictionary, you'll just see one symbol, whether it's a light L or a dark L.
当你在字典中查看单词的国际音标转录时，无论是轻 L 还是重 L，你只会看到一个符号。
It's up to you to know when to make a dark L when the L comes at the end of a syllable.
当 L 在音节的结尾时，你需要知道何时发重 L。
Remember, we're talking about sounds and not letters.
记住，我们谈论的是声音而不是字母。
In the example, Google, you see the letter E after the L.
在例子中，Google，你会看到 L 后面有字母 E。
E is a vowel.
E 是一个元音。
But when you look at the phonetic transcription of the word, the last sound is the L.
但当你查看单词的音标转录时，最后一个声音是 L。
So the L in Google is a dark L, L, L.
所以 Google 中的 L 是重 L，L，L。
Google.
Google。
If you integrate a good dark L into your speech, it will help you sound more American.
如果你在讲话中融入一个好的重 L，它会帮助你听起来更像美国人。
The light L, lack, slow.
轻 L，lack，slow。
The dark L, feel, recall.
重 L，feel，recall。
Example words.
示例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
L, love.
L，love。
Hello.
Hello。
L, hello.
L，hello。
Flat.
Flat。
L, flat.
L，flat。
Feel.
Feel。
L, feel.
L，feel。
Table.
Table。
L, table.
L，table。
People.
People。
L, people.
L，people。
The M consonant sound.
M 辅音。
This sound is simply made by pressing the lips together lightly, mm, while making a sound with the vocal cords.
这个声音很简单，通过轻轻合上嘴唇，mm，同时用声带发出声音。
So this is a voiced consonant, mm.
所以这是一个有声的辅音，mm。
The teeth may begin to part a little in preparation for the next sound, mm, which will pull the lips a little bit, mm.
牙齿可能会开始稍微分开，为下一个声音做准备，mm，这会稍微拉动嘴唇，mm。
Because the soft palate is lowered, air comes up through the nasal passages, this makes it a nasal consonant.
因为软腭降低，空气通过鼻腔，这使得它成为一个鼻音辅音。
You can feel the vibration in your nose.
你可以感觉到鼻子里的振动。
Mm.
嗯。
There are only three nasal sounds in American English.
美式英语中只有三个鼻音。
Mm.
嗯。
Let's look at this sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个声音。
The word mom.
单词“mom”。
Lips press together as the jaw drops a little bit.
嘴唇合在一起，颌骨稍微下垂。
Another M at the end.
结尾处的另一个M。
Lips press together.
嘴唇合在一起。
Summer.
“Summer”。
Lips press together.
嘴唇合在一起。
The M consonant.
M辅音。
Mom.
“Mom”。
Summer.
“Summer”。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Make.
“Make”。
Mm.
嗯。
Make.
“Make”。
My.
“My”。
Mm.
嗯。
My.
“My”。
Forming.
“Forming”。
Mm.
嗯。
Forming.
“Forming”。
Dim.
“Dim”。
Mm.
嗯。
Dim.
“Dim”。
Mistake.
“Mistake”。
Mm.
嗯。
Mistake.
“Mistake”。
Game.
“Game”。
Mm.
嗯。
Game.
“Game”。
The N consonant sound.
N辅音音。
To make this sound, the jaw drops a little, and the lips part.
发这个音时，颌骨稍微下垂，嘴唇分开。
Mm.
嗯。
The front, flat part of the tongue goes to the roof of the mouth.
舌头的前平部分到达上颚。
Make sure to keep your tongue wide as you do that.
确保在这样做时保持舌头宽。
The soft palate is lowered.
软腭降低。
Air comes up through the nasal passages.
空气通过鼻腔通道上升。
This makes it a nasal consonant.
这使它成为一个鼻音辅音。
You can feel the vibration in your nose.
你可以感觉到鼻子里的振动。
Mm.
嗯。
There are only three nasal sounds in American English.
美式英语中只有三个鼻音。
Mm.
嗯。
It's very important that the tongue be relaxed.
舌头放松非常重要。
If there's tension in the back of the tongue, it will sound somewhat like the NG sound, even if the front of the tongue is in the right position.
如果舌头后部有紧张感，即使舌头前部在正确位置，也会听起来有点像NG音。
One thing that will help relaxation is to think about keeping the tongue really wide.
帮助放松的一件事是想象保持舌头非常宽。
Mm.
嗯。
Let's look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察。
The N sound.
N音。
Lips relaxed, tongue wide and lifted to the roof of the mouth.
嘴唇放松，舌头宽并抬到上颚。
If you see any darkness on the sides of the tongue when you practice, that means there's tension in the tongue.
如果练习时看到舌头两侧有黑暗，那就意味着舌头有紧张感。
Try to release that tension and keep the tongue wide.
试着释放这种紧张感，保持舌头宽。
The word NO.
单词“NO”。
Tongue soft, relaxed, and wide.
舌头柔软、放松且宽。
The word SNAG.
单词“SNAG”。
Front of the tongue to roof of mouth.
舌头前部到上颚。
The word ON.
单词“ON”。
Wide tongue to the roof of the mouth to finish the word.
宽舌头到上颚以完成单词。
The N consonant sound.
N辅音音。
NO.
“NO”。
SNAG.
“SNAG”。
ON.
“ON”。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Nice.
“Nice”。
Nn.
嗯。
Nice.
“Nice”。
One.
“One”。
Nn.
嗯。
One.
“One”。
Number.
“Number”。
Nn.
嗯。
Number.
“Number”。
Woman.
“Woman”。
Nn.
嗯。
Woman.
“Woman”。
Win.
“Win”。
Nn.
嗯。
Win.
“Win”。
Any.
“Any”。
Nn.
嗯。
Any.
“Any”。
End.
“End”。
Nn.
嗯。
End.
“End”。
The NG consonant sound.
NG辅音音。
To make this sound, the jaw drops a little bit.
发这个音时，颌骨稍微下垂。
Nn.
嗯。
The lips part and the back part of the tongue stretches all the way up to the soft palate.
嘴唇分开，舌头后部伸展到软腭。
The tongue tip is forward.
舌尖向前。
Because the soft palate is lowered, air comes up through the nasal passages.
因为软腭降低，空气通过鼻腔通道上升。
This makes it a nasal consonant.
这使它成为一个鼻音辅音。
You can feel the vibration in your nose.
你可以感觉到鼻子里的振动。
Nn.
嗯。
There are only three nasal sounds in American English.
美式英语中只有三个鼻音。
Nn, Nn, Nn.
嗯，嗯，嗯。
Let's study it up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作研究它。
A relaxed, lowered jaw.
放松、下垂的颌骨。
Since this sound is made at the back of the mouth, it's hard to get a clear picture of it.
由于这个音是在口腔后部发出的，很难清楚地看到它。
The tongue lifts in the back while the tip stays down and forward.
舌头在后部抬起，而舌尖保持向下和向前。
The word RING.
单词“RING”。
The tongue lifts in the back while the tip stays down and forward.
舌头在后部抬起，而舌尖保持向下和向前。
Lips are relaxed.
嘴唇放松。
The word ALONG.
单词“ALONG”。
Since the tongue is low for the vowel before, it's easier to see the tongue lift in the back.
由于元音前舌头较低，更容易看到舌头在后部抬起。
And now it's lifted in the back with relaxed lips.
现在它在后部抬起，嘴唇放松。
The word FINGER.
单词“FINGER”。
Again, the tongue lifts in the back while the tip stays down and forward.
再次，舌头在后部抬起，而舌尖保持向下和向前。
This sound can occur in the middle or at the end of a word in American English, but not at the beginning.
这个音可以在美式英语中出现在单词中间或结尾，但不能在开头。
The NG consonant.
NG辅音。
Ring.
“Ring”。
Along.
“Along”。
Finger.
“Finger”。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Anger.
“Anger”。
Nng.
嗯。
Anger.
“Anger”。
Song.
“Song”。
Nng.
嗯。
Song.
“Song”。
Wing.
“Wing”。
Nng.
嗯。
Wing.
“Wing”。
English.
“English”。
Nng.
嗯。
English.
“English”。
Single.
“Single”。
Nng.
嗯。
Single.
“Single”。
Beginning.
“Beginning”。
Nng.
嗯。
Beginning.
“Beginning”。
The W sound.
W音。
To make this sound, wuh, the lips form a tight circle.
发这个音时，嘴唇形成一个紧密的圆圈。
Wuh.
嗯。
The back part of the tongue stretches up towards the soft palate, while the front part of the tongue lightly touches the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌头后部向软腭伸展，而舌头前部轻轻触碰下前牙的后面。
To give this sound the right quality, you have to close the vocal cords to get this sound, wuh, wuh, wuh, which we add to the sound, wuh.
为了给这个音正确的质量，你必须闭合声带来发出这个音，然后我们将其添加到音中。
You release the vocal cords as you release the lips coming out of the W sound.
当你从W音中释放嘴唇时，释放声带。
Wuh.
嗯。
Let's look at the sound up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这个音。
With the tight circle for the lips, you can't see the tongue at all.
由于嘴唇的紧密圆圈，你完全看不到舌头。
But it lifts in the back.
但它在后部抬起。
The word, Y.
单词“Y”。
A tight circle for the lips.
嘴唇的紧密圆圈。
The word, West.
单词“West”。
Again, a tight circle for the lips.
再次，嘴唇的紧密圆圈。
The word, unwind.
单词“unwind”。
Here, the W is in the middle of the word.
这里，W在单词中间。
We still take the time to bring the lips into a tight circle.
我们仍然花时间将嘴唇形成一个紧密的圆圈。
Even at the beginning of words.
即使在单词开头。
It doesn't occur at the end of any words, though the letter W does.
它不会出现在任何单词的结尾，尽管字母W会。
The W consonant.
W辅音。
Y.
“Y”。
West.
“West”。
Unwind.
“Unwind”。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Water.
“Water”。
Wuh.
嗯。
Water.
“Water”。
Welcome.
“Welcome”。
Wuh.
嗯。
Welcome.
“Welcome”。
Rework.
“Rework”。
Wuh.
嗯。
Rework.
“Rework”。
Away.
“Away”。
Wuh.
嗯。
Away.
“Away”。
Between.
“Between”。
Wuh.
嗯。
Between.
“Between”。
Will.
“Will”。
Wuh.
嗯。
Will.
“Will”。
The Y consonant.
Y辅音。
To make the Y sound, the jaw drops a little bit.
发Y音时，颌骨稍微下垂。
Yuh.
嗯。
The lips may be relaxed, or they may begin to take the position of the next sound.
嘴唇可以放松，也可以开始采取下一个音的姿势。
The tongue tip is down, lightly touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
舌尖向下，轻轻触碰下前牙的后面。
The middle part of the tongue lifts and touches the roof of the mouth.
舌头中部抬起并触碰上颚。
It pushes forward against the roof of the mouth.
它向前推压上颚。
Before pulling away.
然后拉开。
As we push the tongue forward on the roof of the mouth, we close the vocal cords to get this sound.
当我们将舌头向前推压上颚时，我们闭合声带来发出这个音。
Which we add to the sound.
然后我们将其添加到音中。
We release them the same time we release the tongue.
我们在释放舌头的同时释放它们。
Relaxed jaw drop, and the lips are relaxed.
放松的颌骨下垂，嘴唇放松。
The tongue tip is down, while the middle of the tongue presses forward against the roof of the mouth.
舌尖向下，而舌头中部向前推压上颚。
The word YES.
单词“YES”。
The tongue tip is down, while the middle of the tongue presses forward against the roof of the mouth.
舌尖向下，而舌头中部向前推压上颚。
The tongue releases into the EH as in BED vowel.
舌头放松成像在单词BED中的EH元音。
The word Youth.
单词Youth。
Notice how the lips begin to round for the next sound.
注意嘴唇如何开始为下一个音圆润。
The OO as in BOO vowel.
像在单词BOO中的OO元音。
The tongue tip is down, while the middle of the tongue presses forward against the roof of the mouth.
舌尖向下，而舌头的中部向前压在上颚。
Releasing into the EH as in BED vowel.
放松成像在单词BED中的EH元音。
This sound is most common at the beginning of words.
这个音在单词开头最常见。
It doesn't occur at the end of any words, though the letter Y does.
它不会出现在任何单词的结尾，尽管字母Y会。
The Y sound.
Y音。
Yes.
是的。
Youth.
青年。
Yell.
喊叫。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Yeah.
是啊。
Yuh.
Yuh。
Yeah.
是啊。
Unusual.
不寻常。
Yuh.
Yuh。
Unusual.
不寻常。
Senior.
高级。
Yuh.
Yuh。
Senior.
高级。
You.
你。
Yuh.
Yuh。
You.
你。
Yesterday.
昨天。
Yuh.
Yuh。
Yesterday.
昨天。
Yellow.
黄色。
Yuh.
Yuh。
Yellow.
黄色。
I'm so glad you've taken the time to watch this video.
我很高兴你花时间观看这个视频。
Really understanding the mouth positions for the sounds of American English can help you gain greater clarity in your spoken English.
真正理解美式英语的口腔位置可以帮助你在口语中获得更大的清晰度。
We also have a compilation video on all the vowel and diphthong sounds.
我们还有一个关于所有元音和双元音的合集视频。
I'll put a link to that video in the video description.
我会在视频描述中放上那个视频的链接。
For now, keep your learning going with this video, and don't forget to subscribe with notifications on.
现在，继续通过这个视频学习，不要忘记订阅并打开通知。
I love being your English teacher.
我喜欢做你的英语老师。
That's it, and thanks so much for using Rachel's English.
就是这样，非常感谢你使用Rachel's English。